JD Fillmore

Front-End Developer, UI Designer

Profile

Seasoned front end developer & UI designer with years of experience working on national brand & SaaS products. Skilled in WCAG / AODA AA accessibility, JavaScript / CSS frameworks & design software. Dedicated to my craft through learning new technologies / techniques. Lead teams, projects and internal initiatives, forward-thinking and create clean, re-usable code & documentation.

Skills

- HTML5
- · CSS3 / SCSS
- JavaScript (ES6)
- Flexbox Bootstrap React
- GatsbvJS JAMStack

Netlify

Github

NPM

Git

 Yarn Gulp

Axios

Fetch API

- InVision
- Storybook
- Google Analytics
- SFO
- Photoshop · WCAG / AODA AA Sketch Accessibility
- Aaile
- Scrum
- · Continuous Deployment

Professional Experience

VelocityEHS, Oakville, ON - Front-End Developer

Develop front-end for web application using HTML5, CSS3, Flexbox, SCSS, JavaScript & React

- 50% increase in efficiency through developing a Storybook code component library
- Team lead for AODA WCAG AA Compliance & Storybook integration

Infused Agency (Freelance), Remote - Front-End Developer, UI / UX Designer

- Design and build websites using GatsbyJS (React), HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Flexbox and JavaScript
- 40% increase in client sales due to accessibility, speed and performance of websites
- · 60% increase in all clients overall SEO rankings due to on-page and off-page SEO efforts
- · Utilize Agile and Scrum methodologies

Thrillworks, Burlington, ON - Front-End Developer

April 2018 - June 2019

June 2019 - Present

April 2013 - Present

- · Developed internal AODA AA accessibility websites using GatsbyJS (React), HTML5, CSS3, Flexbox, SCSS and JavaScript
- · 50% increase in team efficiency by co-developing an internal Storybook code component library
- · 40% increase in organization by co-developing WorkShare an internal project tracking system
- · Utilized Agile and Scrum methodologies

Virtual Image, Hamilton, ON - Front-End Developer, UI / UX Designer

September 2016 - April 2018

- Designed and developed websites using Adobe XD, Photoshop, HTML5, CSS3, Flexbox, SCSS and JavaScript
- · 60% decrease in development time of websites due to component based libraries
- In charge of project and client management, leading to a large increase in satisfaction

Elite Digital, Toronto, ON - Front-End Developer, UI / UX Designer (Contract)

March 2016 - September 2016

- First 2 days of employment, hand-coded and launched European Union website
- Developed responsive microsites for The NHL, Pepsi, Rogers and Disney using HTML5, CSS3, SCSS and JavaScript
- 5 websites designed and launched within the first week of employment

iOPW, Toronto, ON - Front-End Developer, UI / UX Designer

August 2014 - March 2016

- 30% increase in revenue due to successful design of rwardz.com front-end and back-end
- Designed and developed 30 websites using Adobe XD, Photoshop, HTML5, CSS, SCSS and JavaScript
- · Managed team of junior front-end and back-end developers, as well as numerous clients

Side Projects

Maple Leafs API - React, React Hooks, Styled Components, JavaScript, Axios, REST API Movie Database API - React, CSS3, SCSS, JavaScript, Axios, REST API

Final Fantasy 7 Stats - ReactJS, JavaScript, CSS3, SCSS, JSON

Cass-A-Bella Construction (Client) - React, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, JavaScript, Gatsby

MC Aesthetics (Client) - React, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, JavaScript, Gatsby

Education

Advanced Diploma, Multimedia Design, Oshawa, ON -Durham College

Interests

Playing guitar, songwriting, open mics, working out, craft beer, spending time with my wife and daughter, tinkering and learning